ul.com 2001-07-24

# UL Privacy Statement

## PRIVACY STATEMENT

UL respects the privacy of its customers and users of this site. This Privacy Statement is designed to help you understand what information we gather and what we do with that information.

## What Information Does UL Collect?

**Information We Gather**

The type of information gathered by UL falls into three general categories:

  1. General tracking information gathered as visitors navigate through certain parts of the site;
  2. Personal information you provide when you register to use our UL IQ™ for Plastics Database; and
  3. Personal information associated with subscribing to our UL IQ™ Link Program.

**General Tracking Information**

To help us tailor our site to the needs and interests of our visitors we keep track of certain pages visited by users. We aggregate this data with data on the pages visited by other users to track overall visitor traffic patterns. We use this information to improve our site by making it more responsive to the needs of our users.

Our webserver automatically collects your IP address when you request pages from our server. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers connected to the Internet to identify your computer so the data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you. This information does not identify you personally.

**UL IQ™ for Plastics Database**

If you browse the UL IQ™ for Plastics Database, we use cookies to track your use of that database. You must accept this cookie in order to gain access to the database. A cookie is just an entry in a text file or folder on your hard drive. The cookie contains a unique ID number assigned to you for the duration of a single session that allows you to search the database. When you return for subsequent visits to the database, a new cookie will be assigned to you for that session. 

Cookies do not reveal personal information; the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. Cookies cannot read data off your hard disk. If you would like more technical information about how a cookie works, please [click here](http://www.howstuffworks.com/cookie.htm).

When you register to use the UL IQ™ for Plastics Database you must provide some personal information such as your name, company name, title, e-mail address, address, and certain demographic information (phone number is optional.)

**UL IQ™ Link Program**

If you subscribe to the UL IQ™ Link Program, you must provide your name, company name, title, e-mail address and certain demographic information (phone number is optional.)

## What Does UL Do With The Information It Collects?

**What We Do With The Information We Gather**

As indicated above, the aggregated tracking information we gather over the site is used to tailor the site to our users' interests.

**UL IQ™ for Plastics Database**

The information you provide to UL to use the UL IQ™ for Plastics Database is collected and used so that, from time to time, we can send you information on programs and services that we believe may be of interest to you. If you would prefer not to receive such information, please check the box at the bottom of the registration screen. If you do not check that box, but later want to have the UL staff remove your e-mail address from our list, please send an e-mail address to [webmaster@us.ul.com](mailto:webmaster@us.ul.com) and include the word "remove." If you ask us to make the change for you, please allow at least forty-eight business hours for implementation. We reserve the right to disclose information about your usage and demographics, provided that it will not reveal your personal identity in connection with the disclosure of such information.

**UL IQ™ Link Program**

If you are a participant in the UL IQ™ Link Program, we use the information you provide to fulfill your subscription request, send you an e-mail confirming your subscription, and from time to time e-mail/mail information for the purpose of informing you of any change or additions to the UL IQ™ Link Program.

**What We Don't Do With The Information We Gather**

Even though we've said it already, the message is important enough to state again. UL respects your privacy. We will NOT sell or otherwise provide any of your personal information to any third party without your permission unless required to do so by law or in good faith belief if such action is necessary or desirable to comply with the law, protect or defend the rights of property of UL, this site or its users.

**What About the Information Collected by Other Web Sites that this Web Site Links To?**

If you choose to leave this UL site via links to other non-UL sites, including those provided by the UL IQ™ Link Program participants, UL is not responsible for the privacy policies or content of those sites, nor is UL responsible for the cookies those sites might deposit on your hard drive.

_Last Updated On July 17, 2001_
